whether you're an athlete or not
hydration is an essential part of life
staying adequately hydrated can help
regulate your body temperature and keep
your organs functioning properly among
many other benefits while drinking water
is enough for your daily life bodily
functions you're not getting enough
electrolytes you're not going to find
yourself hydrated after a long workout
session where you've been sweating a lot
after you've been sick or even just a
long night out on the town this is where
products like liquid IVs hydration
multiplier really come into play Just
One of these small packets is the
equivalent of three bottles of water
they're vegan gluten-free and non-GMO so
if you're tired of you know your typical
sports drink or slamming you know a
bunch of glasses of water every day you
might want to snag some of these we got
a lot to talk about today so let's go
ahead and get after it
[Music]
thank you
what's up everyone it's Jake back in the
barbing garage gym and for today's video
I'm going to be breaking down liquid
IV's hydration multiplier in this video
today I'm going to tell you everything
you need to know about this product from
the price the ingredients some pros and
cons most importantly though who should
purchase these and who shouldn't now
before I get going with all that we've
actually reviewed a ton of electrolyte
supplements on barbin.com so if you want
to browse our best list all you need to
do is search barbin best electrolyte
supplements it's going to pull right up
for you you can find out for yourself
which ones that we like the best
okay so let's talk about what I like
about liquid IVs hydration multiplier I
think the first thing I'm going to talk
about is you know just the ease of use
really simple you know just one of these
packets you just rip it open toss it in
your water bottle give it a good Shake
it's going to dissolve I'll show you
guys you know later about how fast it
dissolves also this is really good for
being on the go if somebody travels a
lot you know whatever you take it to
work with you even that's really nice
right there also you're going to be
getting about three times the amount of
electrolytes compared to a similar size
sports drink so you mix this with 16
ounces of water you compare that to a 16
ounce sports drink you're going to be
getting about 300 more milligrams of
sodium and potassium compared to that
sports drink which is also you know
really nice I think they taste great I
really like this lemon lime right here
there's 12 different flavors you can
choose from though so it's nice there's
plenty of variety and in addition to
these packets being gluten free and
non-GMO they're also vegan friendly so
that's really nice too
all right okay so there aren't very many
Cons with this product but there's still
a couple that I want to touch on because
you know you might run into that so
let's talk about money first with liquid
IV I definitely think you want to go
down the bulk route rather than this
right here so I got a 10 pack right here
from the grocery store right around 20
bucks including tax so basically every
single one of these packets is two
dollars now that's still cheaper than
one single Gatorade but that's
definitely worth mentioning all expand
on pricing in a minute you know just
wanted to bring that up and then I also
want to talk about the sodium and the
sugar content with these packets so
you're gonna be getting 22 of your daily
value of both of those and that's kind
of high you know even compared to a
Gatorade so if you're not you know Super
Active and sweating a lot and we're
trying to replenish what you lost in a
tough workout for example
this really isn't going to be you know
an everyday drink kind of thing and then
there's also people who just want to you
know limit the amount of sugar and
sodium they get on a daily basis so you
definitely want to keep that at the
Forefront of your mind
all right so let's talk about some money
now with liquid IVs hydration multiplier
and you can purchase this you know on
Amazon at your local grocery store or of
course you know through the liquid IV
website so you can get an eight pack off
Amazon for about 17 or so it kind of
just depends on the popularity of the
flavor and everything at your local
grocery store it's gonna cost you about
20 bucks for a 10 pack but honestly if
you're looking for the best you know
bang for your buck bulk purchase
definitely head over to that liquid IV
website so let's talk about those for
just one quick second all right so a 16
pack off their website's about 25 bucks
a 32 packs around fifty dollars the 48
pack is found 75 bucks and the 64 packs
can run you around 100 basically now
regardless of which one you choose the
packets are going to be around a dollar
and 56 cents unless you go for that
monthly subscription where you get that
monthly refill they're gonna drop around
a dollar and 20 cents per packet and
honestly this is a really solid deal
considering the overall effectiveness
but also you know it's going to be a
cheaper alternative you know as opposed
to a Gatorade or any other sports drink
all right so let's take a second and
talk about some of the ingredients that
are in liquid IVs hydration multiplier
and remember once again these are vegan
gluten-free and non-GMO so that's really
nice for obvious reasons now once again
remember you're getting 22 of your daily
value of sugar and sodium in one of
these packets so if you wanted to keep
you know one or both of those down on a
daily basis definitely keep that in mind
all right so in addition to that you're
going to be getting eight percent of
your daily potassium intake 80 percent
of vitamin C 140 of niacin 130 of
vitamin B6 280 of vitamin B12 and 230
percent of pantothenic acid which is
vitamin B5 it's a fancy word for it and
that's really going to help turn what
you're eating or in this case drinking
into energy let's talk about the CTT
technology which is cellular transport
technology essentially this is what
liquid IV claims to be you know the
optimal ratio of nutrients it's going to
help you know transport the hydration
through your bloodstream at a faster
rate essentially that's what that is but
there's other there's a couple other
things that I want to talk about as well
so they're using Stevia leaf extract for
their sweetener it's roughly 200 to 400
times sweeter than sugar also contains
zero calories which actually is only 45
calories within one of these packets so
that's really nice citric acid is going
to help stabilize the flavor and
potassium citrate is going to help carry
the nutrients through the body plus that
can help prevent muscle cramps and even
improve bone health so there's a lot
going on here you know there's plenty
other ingredients on the website that I
definitely advise you to go and check
out just so you know everything about it
and you've dot all your eyes and cross
all your teeth
and when it comes to Flavors you know
once again you have 12 different options
to choose from including a variety pack
so once again I have lemon lime right
here there's a tropical punch there's
pina colada there's grape there's
strawberry lemonade y'all there's a lot
to choose from which is a really nice
touch
okay so before I actually demonstrate
you know how fast these packets dissolve
into my bottle of water right here I
wanted to go ahead and compare this
Gatorade to one of these packets so
let's talk about the calories first it's
worth mentioning this is a 20 ounce
bottle of Gatorade but with this bottle
you're getting 140 calories compared to
the 45 that are within this liquid IV
packet I also want to talk about sodium
you're getting 12 percent of sodium as
opposed to 22 so if you're somebody who
wants to limit your sodium now this
Gatorade might actually be better for
you right there but when it comes to
sugars you're getting 69 of your daily
value with this Gatorade bottle right
here as opposed to the 22. so I thought
22 was high 69 that's kind of ridiculous
honestly so if you're somebody who wants
to limit that Sugar you know Gatorade is
obviously not the way to go and then
actually you're only getting 80
milligrams of potassium which is
technically zero percent of your daily
value you know as opposed to the eight
percent you're getting right here with
the liquid IV so these are just some
things to keep in mind you know you can
be on both sides of the spectrum on
which one actually suits your needs the
best Okay so let's go ahead and get to
the fun part now I'm gonna rip open this
packet and toss it in this bottle of
water
and just show you how easy and it
dissolves and everything so put this guy
in here
trying to shake it up
now they don't say you know how long you
should shake it or anything I think it's
really just however you want to do it
now it's going to be cloudy as you can
see
it's just because of the sodium you know
that's really just all that it is but
you know I don't know if you can really
tell up close but it did dissolve really
well I mean there might be a couple
specs floating around honestly can't
tell if that's just bubbles or not
though it's honestly that's really nice
you know it only takes a couple of
seconds for it to fully dissolve within
the water and we got to do a taste test
right
really good I mean definitely takes like
lemon lime it is pretty sugary
and it's a little tart I guess you could
say so you could always you know dilute
this packet with more water this is 16
ounces you can do 20 ounces you could do
more and kind of keep that taste down
but honestly tastes pretty good to me
and I'm sure you'll probably like it as
well
all right so let's talk about who should
or maybe should not purchase liquid IVs
hydration multiplier and I want to start
with who should so if somebody who's you
know constantly on the go the
convenience aspect of these packets is
just you know Top Notch you can throw
one in your bag throw it in your pocket
and you're good to go it's really easy
also if you hate the taste of water and
you think it's really Bland you know
it's really nice there's 12 different
flavor options for you to choose from
even that variety pack and I haven't
been able to taste all of them
unfortunately but I'm really confident
about this lemon lime and I'm sure the
other ones taste you know pretty good as
well and also you know if you're
somebody who sweats a lot you're an
athlete you work out really hard and
you're worried about the amount of
sodium you're losing while you're
sweating you know the sodium content
here is going to be really nice for you
and then when it comes to those who
might not want to purchase this really
y'all it just boils down to the sodium
and the sugar content so remember you're
getting 22 of your daily value of both
of those so for somebody who wants to
keep at that at a minimum then this
isn't the product for you
well friends that's all I got for you
today on liquid IV's hydration
multiplier honestly all these are great
after a tough workout a long day in the
Sun a long night out on the town and
really just for overall hydration
they're super convenient you know you
can take them on the road with you and
they taste really great in my opinion
just remember buying them in bulk is
absolutely the way to go and if you're
somebody who wants to limit your sodium
and sugar intake on a daily basis you
know these really might not be you know
the best option out there for you thanks
for watching y'all I hope this video was
really helpful and that I was able to
break down everything you need to know
about this product as always keep your
eyes peeled for my next video but for
now head over to barbin.com so we have a
full written review ready to go for
y'all all you gotta do is search barban
liquid IV review article will pull up
you can go over everything we talked
about here today I'll catch y'all next
time
thank you